## JOSHUA WEISBROD-TORRES

Dallas, TX 75208

Phone: 254-291-9660 | Email: joshuaweisbrodtorres@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-weisbrod-torres/ Portfolio: https://joshuaweisbrodtorres.github.io/portfolio-react/

GitHub: https://github.com/joshuaweisbrodtorres/

### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience as an educator who is passionate about learning and teaching others. Known for strong creativity, problem solving skills, and handling multiple tasks at once. Superior knowledge in music and the arts. Graduate of the Full Stack Development program through the University of Texas at Austin.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT

Applications: GitHub, jQuery, MomentJs, NodeJS, Materialize

### **PROJECTS**

### MaskD: Post Pandemic Dating

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/joshuaweisbrodtorres/post-pandemic-dating/">https://github.com/joshuaweisbrodtorres/post-pandemic-dating/</a> Deployed: <a href="https://joshuaweisbrodtorres.github.io/post-pandemic-dating/">https://joshuaweisbrodtorres.github.io/post-pandemic-dating/</a>

- An application to display date ideas for singles going back on the dating scene and couples going out on a romantic date. User inputs were taken to display weather, holidays, events, and restaurant/food around the city they input.
- Lead developer of a group of 5.
- Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MomentJs, Materialize:CSS, Materialize:JS, Google Fonts and Icons, WeatherAPI, Calendarific API, Ticketmaster API, Zomato API, TheCocktailDB API, GIT, and Github

#### Weather Checker

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/joshuaweisbrodtorres/what-is-your-weather">https://github.com/joshuaweisbrodtorres/what-is-your-weather</a>
Deployed: <a href="https://joshuaweisbrodtorres.github.io/what-is-your-weather">https://joshuaweisbrodtorres.github.io/what-is-your-weather</a>

- An application to check the weather in major cities around the world.
- Built the front end and used API to display weather for user input.
- Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Google Fonts, OpenWeatherAPI, GIT, and Github

#### EXPERIENCE

## Assistant Band Director Duncanville Independent School District

2019-Present

Duncanville,TX

Develop and reshape courses to the level the students were performing on.

• Manage a middle school band program that includes 180+ students, develop courses for students both in person and digitally, and create promotional digital media for the department.

### Assistant Band Director

2017-2019

Red Oak.TX

### Red Oak Independent School District

Charged with overseeing band performances, trips, and mentorship of the performers.

- Spearheaded a middle and high school band program that included 400+ students, conducted a successful band in concerts, and worked closely with the Fine Arts department for many collaborations.
- Organized two successful trips (one out of state and one in state) for 125+ people.
- Took the first successful sub-non-varsity band in the ten years prior.
- Helped with the band's highest placement on the road to State Marching Contest.

# **Teacher of Record/Graduate Teaching Assistant Texas State University**

2015-2017

San Marcos,TX

Instructed the undergraduate Woodwinds methods course.

- Trusted by the department head to assist in teaching additional classes as needed.
- Taught instruments to college students so they could then teach to school aged children.

## Elementary Music Educator Killeen Independent School District

2013-2015

Killeen,TX

Taught music to elementary students which included life skills. Collaborated with classroom teachers on many performances.

Conducted a district wide choir of 100+ students from 5 schools.

### EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Development: University of Texas, Austin, Texas

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, and Node Js.

Masters of Music Education: Texas State University, San Marcos, TX

Bachelors of Music Studies: Texas State University, San Marcos, TX

Concentration with Instrumental Emphasis and Teaching